<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>🌶️</title>
<link>https://john.abumirchi.com/blog/</link>
<atom:link href="https://john.abumirchi.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description></description>
<generator>quarto-1.8.27</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Take the power back</title>
  <dc:creator>John </dc:creator>
  <link>https://john.abumirchi.com/blog/2026_02_28/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Bluesky is where I prefer to do my social mediaing. Like most sites it has a particular perspective on things and the overwhelming attitude towards AI is something along the lines of: Industrial plaerism machine. Most of this is due to how AI is encountered. It’s filling all of our social media feeds, google search results are garbage now, creepy folks are using with their personal surveilance glassed to be creeps in public. All these things are true. The refrain you hear from many folks is: AI is only good at programming, I’m not a programmer, and I want nothing to do with it.</p>
<p>You may not be a programmer, but you most certainly use software. Software is largely created by large corporations and most of us are consumers. We wait for companies to release it and then we use it. If it doesnt work or just works poorly, we may complaine about it. Though most companies are too large and the software they produce is targeting a broad audience. Consequently this means our suggestions and greiviences are not likely to gain any traction. So what is a non-programmer to do?</p>
<p>You may not be a programmer but with Claude Code you can certainly create software. Not only can you create softwar, you can create software that does what you want. You can control almost every aspect of what you do. And in the process you can take back control over how you use computers and limit how much of your data these giant corporations can harvest.</p>
<p>I’ve been exploring these ideas with a series of projects and I want to take this space to expand on that a bit. Here is a list of what I’ve done and I will expand on these in detail in the future:</p>
<ul>
<li>Creating this blog and pkgdown site.</li>
<li>Integrating health data from Apple and other sources to track my health and fitness goals.</li>
<li>Creating a local archive of all of my email going back to the 90s and a gmail-like interface that allows me to search and actually find information.</li>
<li>Creating my own youtube archiving and recommendation algorithm.</li>
<li>Combining my data from streaming sites to allow me to actually find TV shows and movies I want to watch.</li>
<li>Building my own PDF viewer/editor that works the way I think it should, with only the features it should, and essentially removing my need to buy Adobe Acrobat.</li>
<li>Creating a custom DVR to manage my security cameras.</li>
<li>Creating a service to manage all of this that allows me to assign service tickets (for bug fixes and new features) that calls Claude Code to resolve those tickets.</li>
</ul>



 ]]></description>
  <category>Science</category>
  <category>Data</category>
  <guid>https://john.abumirchi.com/blog/2026_02_28/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Crossing the Streams</title>
  <link>https://john.abumirchi.com/blog/2026_02_25/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>In my next example of using Claude Code to take back control of how I use services I’ll start with a problem. I sit down with my wife and kid and I want to watch a movie. Which movie? I go to Netflix it has suggestions and a list that I’ve been curating for a while. So I go to my watch list and start looking. But there is no way to sort this. So I scroll trying to remember what these movies are about. Then I go to Prime Video. Same thing. There is no way for me to get these services to talk to each other and they have control over everything. Even how what I want to see is sorted and displayed.</p>
<p>So what do I do?</p>
<p>Well GDPR is a great thing in many ways. Because of GDPR I can export all this information from these services. So I did this with Netflix and Prime Video. But what do I do with that? I go to claude code and I tell it I want to import it all into a service that will allow me to combine my watch lists, what I have watched in the past, and what I’ve liked or disliked in the past.</p>
<p>Now this isn’t automatic. I have to go back and forth on things. Likes for example. They are different on Netflix (thumbs down, +1 thumb up, 2 thumbs up or neutral) vs Prime video (up, down or netural). And the names of titles are not standardized, so I have to work with claude on how they are matched. You can see the import dialog below. It took a few shots with each service to get it right for me.</p>
<p>Next I tell claude: Hey I want you to dump everything into a default playlist. And then give me the ability to create new playlists. When I view playlists I want to be able to filter them by type or ratings. I want to be able to sort them by genera. This helps me to find something appropriate in the moment.</p>
<p>I can control what is shown in popups. Here I have it show me the year, how many stars, the primary language and the genres. I have it show above or below the title so if I want I can add/remove the playlists it’s in. I can also rate it myself.</p>
<p>When I click on a title I can control how the details look. Here I have a lot of the same information but I also have links out to streaming services. So if I want to watch it I can go to where ever it’s available. I had claude also provide a more like this option to find similar movies. And I had it embed Youtube trailers for the movies as well. Everything I’m showing you here is on my own network at home.</p>
<p>Now I didn’t just import my playlists. I also imported what I’ve viewed before, and my likes. With this information I can create my own For You Page with titles based on my previous viewing habits. I can also customize this. Each user can adjust how this works by specifying reccomendation preferences in their settings. Here you can see I added Britis Crime Drama and Bollywood movies. You can also add keywords and specify languages you prefer movies to be in.</p>
<p>I also wanted a separate set of reccomendations for what is popular and what is going on on streaming services. All the data here is being pulled from public databases and this took about 5 days to put together with Claude Code.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>Science</category>
  <category>Technology</category>
  <guid>https://john.abumirchi.com/blog/2026_02_25/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://john.abumirchi.com/blog/2026_02_25/cover.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
